# **Ryan Scherr**

ryanascherr@gmail.com | 410-292-1432 | Baltimore, Maryland 21228 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ryanascherr | GitHub: github.com/ryanascherr Portfolio: ryanascherr.github.io/portfolio/

# **Summary**

Web developer who specializes in front-end development and draws upon almost a decade of work as a leader and team player in the field Applied behavior Analysis. Through the Coding Bootcamp at Johns Hopkins Engineering, have learned a variety of skills, languages, and frameworks, including Browser-Based Technology, API Interaction, Databases, and Server-Side Development. Passion and expertise in creating web pages with responsive design and intuitive UI, with a focus on mobile-first design and development. Looking forward to finding creative solutions to give users the best possible experience on any project.

## **Technical Skills**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery UI, Node.js, Moment.js, Bootstrap, Materialize, GIT, GitHub, APIs, JSON, MySQL, React.js

# **Applications Built**

Tech Blog | Lead Developer | https://whispering-sea-48503.herokuapp.com/

- A blog where users can post questions and reply to others' questions, with full login functionality
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars.js, Doteny, Bcrypt
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/ryanascherr/tech-blog

Yoda Advice | Co-Developer | https://caitbopp.github.io/yoda-advice/

- A language translator, translating advice into Yoda Speak
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Materialize, Fun Translations API, Advice Slip JSON API
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/caitbopp/yoda-advice

Weather Dashboard | Lead Developer | https://ryanascherr.github.io/weather-dashboard/

- Displays current weather and 5-day forecast of any city
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, iQuery, OpenWeatherMap API
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/ryanascherr/weather-dashboard

Work Day Scheduler | Lead Developer | https://ryanascherr.github.io/work-day-scheduler/

- A scheduler with time slots and fillable fields for each work hour
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Moment.js
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/ryanascherr/work-day-scheduler

Password Generator | Lead Developer | https://ryanascherr.github.io/password-generator/

- Allows creation of a password using a series of customizable specifications
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, iQuery
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/ryanascherr/password-generator

# **Experience**

#### Behavior Analyst, August 2020 - Present

Attain ABA – Baltimore, MD

- Communicated frequently with families to discuss client progress and train on behavioral interventions
- Collaborated with and supervised Registered Behavior Technicians
- Problem solved and collaborated with co-workers to develop treatment plans for clients

### Behavior Analyst I, July 2019 – March 2020

Trellis Services - Columbia, MD

- Designed data collection systems to track and evaluate client progress on treatment plan objectives
- Conducted functional behavioral assessments and wrote progress reports in a timely manner
- Developed treatment plans to address communication, feeding, behavior, ADLs, and social skills
- Supervised and gave feedback to Technicians implementing treatment plans

# Clinical Specialist I, July 2018 – June 2019

Kennedy Krieger Institute, Pediatric Feeding Disorders Program – Baltimore, MD

- Relayed pertinent information to parents / supervisors daily regarding patient progress and setbacks
- · Assisted in the development of individual assessments and treatment plans
- Completed evaluation reports, progress notes, and correspondence in a timely manner
- Initiated and maintained contact with KKI disciplines and outside agencies
- Provided training for parents, teachers, and/or staff

## **Education**

# Johns Hopkins Coding Boot Camp – Baltimore, MD

Certificate – Full Stack Web Development (August 2021)

## **Behavior Analyst Certification Board**

Board Certified Behavior Analyst (May 2019)

#### **University of Maryland, Baltimore County** – *Baltimore, MD*

M.A. in Human Services, Applied Behavior Analysis (December 2018)

#### Stevenson University - Owings Mills, MD

B.S. in Psychology (May 2015)